SCOTT CARLSON

NYC Metropolitan Area (201) 232-1522 Contact@stcarlson.com

Professional Summary

Software, construction, design, and engineering professional with over 9 years of experience in commercial, residential, and industrial markets. Experience includes scheduling, planning, risk analysis, risk mitigation, project management, building information modeling (BIM), cost estimating, surveying, procurement, construction safety, design, engineering, customer success, marketing, and branding.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Architectural Engineering

2014

University of Cincinnati - Cincinnati, OH

Bachelor of Science: Construction Management

2014

University of Cincinnati - Cincinnati, OH

Work History

Autodesk 09/2019 to Present

Customer Success Manager - New York, NY

- Managing a book of 32 accounts ~ \$7M +.
- Currently driving successful BIM 360 & PlanGrid software implementation to digitize the Architectural, Engineering,
 & Construction (AEC) industry.
- Discovering current business workflows & processes to evaluate problematic, bottlenecked, siloed, and duplicated work.
- Developing training materials and customized training to revolutionize business processes to aid maximum ROI.
- Troubleshooting software issues and working closely with Product Development to enhance product features & functions.
- Analyzing & reporting business trends on a weekly, monthly, and quarterly cadence.

Activate 03/2019 to 09/2018

Marketing Manager - Tri-State Area (NJ)

- Managed a team to drive editorial & promotional messaging within the pharmaceutical industry.
- Implemented marketing materials (brochures, on-boarding kits, flipcharts, sales training, newsletters, emails, websites, informational videos, flashcards, surveys, etc.).
- Defined objectives & messaging for marketing materials & saw materials from inception to execution.

Northeast Remsco Construction

03/2018 to 03/2019

Project Manager – Tri-State Area (NJ/NY)

- Pre-construction scheduling, planning, and coordinating with client, engineering, subcontractors, and vendors.
- Educated owners, engineers, and contractors of potential issues while offering alternate solutions.
- Managed a technical tunneling project for the Alonzo F. Bonsal Wildlife Preserve to ensure proper execution & timely completion; constantly troubleshot errors while exercising risk aversion through planning and scheduling.
- Managed a team of 30; planned & executed construction of the MCUA Sayreville Pump Station Upgrade; including a 1700 - foot floodwall, concrete filled steel pipe piles, steel sheeting with king piles, (6) 60-inch suction valves, underground utilities, & construction of the new building to house 4 new generators.
- Developed strong relationships with many public sector clients, municipalities, & private companies.

Kiewit Corporation 06/2014 to 02/2018

Project Scheduler/Supervisor – (NJ/NY/MA/NC/TX/CA)

- Project Scheduler:
 - o Scheduled 12 simultaneously projects ~ \$3M-600M.

- Scheduled construction of: OGC Plants, Bridges, Tunnels, Solar Fields, Track work (MTA, LIRR, NJ Transit),
 & WWTP.
- O Planned & scheduled deliverables and work efforts including preparation of schedules, tracked actual work against schedules, performed variance analysis studies, and updated schedules weekly.
- Monitored, analyzed, and reported daily production of work performed to meet project schedules and budgets.
- o Forecasted projects to ensure timely completion and identify at-risk jobs.
- Assisted Project Managers and Superintendents in creating short-term / interval schedules, monitor such schedules to determine impact on master schedule, and help in formulating actions to correct scheduling problems.
- Exercised loss aversion by mitigating potential or current risks using schedule delay analysis to prove damage claims when the project was impacted.
- O Designed 3-D architectural models and integrated schedules creating a 4-D environment for clients.
- Worked closely with the cost estimating department; developed estimate schedules, baseline schedules, and models.

Project Manager:

- o Managed 6 crews; 60 laborers & foreman.
- Managed & planned simultaneous projects; identified & mitigated potential issues to meet project deadlines & budgets.
- Oversaw QA/QC & ensured project construction was in accordance with the plans, specifications, submittals, & details.
- o Guided and directed third-party inspectors through project construction, commissioning, and closeout.
- o Materials & Logistics Lead for the Chevron Richmond Refinery Modernization Project. Coordinated with vendors, engineering, & construction team to identify \$2M of misplaced materials.

• Project Estimator:

- o Procured & managed cost estimates for various projects by evaluating contracts, blueprints, & historical data.
- Evaluated bid documents, construction blueprints, and subcontractor material quotes.
- o Prepared accurate estimates of quantities utilizing digitized computer programs.
- o Created a formal proposal for submissions to clients.

Hills Developers, Inc.

01/2013 to 05/2014

Project Estimator/Manager - Cincinnati, OH

- Estimated large luxury apartment complexes ~ \$20-30M.
- Prepared bid packages, negotiated contracts with subcontractors, and managed commercial building construction.

Baker Concrete Construction, Inc.

06/2011 to 03/2012

Field Engineer - Cincinnati, OH

- Surveying, scheduling, and field engineering for the new 360,000 square foot Federal Bureau of Investigation's Biometrics Technology Center (Clarksburg, WV) ~ \$140M.
- Hands on experience with carpentry and masonry work for the renovation and expansion of Washington Park for the Cincinnati Center City Development Corp. (Cincinnati, OH) ~ \$47M.
- Hands on experience with carpentry and masonry work for construction of a 1-story rehabilitation center for the US Army Corps of Engineers (Fort Knox, KY) ~ \$6M.

Al. Never, LLC

01/2011 to 03/2011

Design Build Estimator - Cincinnati, OH

Designed and estimated landscapes & excavations for various construction sites throughout the city of Cincinnati.

Turner Construction Company

06/2010 to 09/2010

VDC/Field/Design Engineer – New York, NY

- Coordinated Building Information Modeling (B.I.M.) meetings.
- Participated in designing Madison Square Garden's renovation, Public School 51, New York Police Academy, and NYU hospital.

Volunteering

Children's Specialized Hospital – Fundraising Committee Chair

08/2018 to Present

 Leading a fundraising team to revitalize a dormant program that gives teens with disabilities the opportunity to make friends and socialize.

Skills

Construction:

- \rightarrow Project scheduling
- \rightarrow Critical thinking
- \rightarrow Problem solving
- \rightarrow Construction safety
- \rightarrow Design/Modeling
- $\stackrel{ o}{ o}$ Client mgmt.
- Customer Success
- QAQC mgmt

- \rightarrow General contracting
- \rightarrow Subcontractor mgmt
- \rightarrow Conflict resolution
- \rightarrow Interpersonal communication
- Data Analytics \rightarrow
- Risk Mitigation/ Risk \rightarrow Analysis

Software:

- \rightarrow Autodesk (AutoCAD, Revit, Navisworks)
- \rightarrow Google SketchUp Pro
- \rightarrow MicroStation
- \rightarrow Synchro LTD
- \rightarrow Adobe Photoshop
- \rightarrow HCSS HeavyJob &
- \rightarrow HeavyBid
- \rightarrow BIM 360
- PlanGrid

- Primavera (P3, P6, Schedule Analyzer, Claim Digger)
- \rightarrow Microsoft (Office, Project)
- \rightarrow SharePoint
- Hard Dollar \rightarrow
- Bluebeam Revu \rightarrow
- Assemble \rightarrow
- BuildingConnected \rightarrow
- TradeTapp \rightarrow
- Pype \rightarrow

Certifications

OSHA 30-Hour; 120 Hr TEFL; Standard First Aid, CPR, & AED; Smartsheet Product Certified User